National Institutional Ranking Framework
Ministry of Education
Government of India
Data Submitted by Institution for India Rankings '2023'
Institute Name: Indian Institute of Technology Delhi [IR-E-I-1074]
Sanctioned (Approved) Intake
Academic Year 2021-22 2020-21 2019-20 2018-19 2017-18 2016-17
UG [4 Years Program(s)] 1093 1071 938 798 - -
UG [5 Years Program(s)] 116 126 123 109 102 -
PG [2 Year Program(s)] 1587 1576 - - - -
Total Actual Student Strength (Program(s) Offered by your Institution)
(All programs No. of Male No. of Female Total Students Within State Outside State Outside Economically Socially No. of students No. of students No. of students No. of students
of all years) Students Students (Including male (Including male Country Backward Challenged receiving full receiving full receiving full who are not
& female) & female) (Including male (Including male (SC+ST+OBC tuition fee tuition fee tuition fee receiving full
& female) & female) Including male reimbursement reimbursement reimbursement tuition fee
& female) from the State from Institution from the Private reimbursement
and Central Funds Bodies
Government
UG [4 Years 3117 723 3840 340 3500 0 273 1914 120 1749 263 55
Program(s)]
UG [5 Years 482 102 584 41 543 0 32 292 7 233 23 61
Program(s)]
PG [2 Year 2555 618 3173 379 2724 70 210 1231 65 555 0 821
Program(s)]
Placement & Higher Studies
UG [4 Years Program(s)]: Placement & Higher Studies for previous 3 years
Academic Year No. of first year No. of first year Academic Year No. of students Academic Year No. of students No. of students Median salary of No. of students
students intake in the students admitted in admitted through graduating in placed placed graduates per selected for Higher
year the year Lateral entry minimum stipulated annum(Amount in Studies
time Rs.)
2016-17 749 751 2017-18 0 2019-20 650 511 1550000(Fifteen Lakh 90
Fifty Thousand)
2017-18 749 750 2018-19 0 2020-21 672 541 1760000(Seventeen 101
Lakh Sixty Thousand )
2018-19 798 790 2019-20 0 2021-22 685 621 2050000(Twenty Lakh 64
Fifty Thousand)
UG [5 Years Program(s)]: Placement & Higher Studies for previous 3 years
Academic Year No. of first year No. of first year Academic Year No. of students Academic Year No. of students No. of students Median salary of No. of students
students intake in the students admitted in admitted through graduating in placed placed graduates per selected for Higher
year the year Lateral entry minimum stipulated annum(Amount in Studies
time Rs.)
2015-16 102 112 2016-17 0 2019-20 88 84 1810000(Eighteen 4
Lakh Ten Thousand)2016-17 102 109 2017-18 0 2020-21 94 77 2200000(Twenty Two 6
Lakh)
2017-18 102 100 2018-19 0 2021-22 80 80 2000000(Twenty Lakh) 0
PG [2 Years Program(s)]: Placement & Higher Studies for previous 3 years
Academic Year No. of first year No. of first year Academic Year No. of students graduating in minimum No. of students Median salary of No. of students
students intake in the students admitted in stipulated time placed placed graduates per selected for Higher
year the year annum(Amount in Studies
Rs.)
2018-19 1045 947 2019-20 653 322 1100000(Eleven 190
Thousand)
2019-20 1169 1181 2020-21 867 379 1500000(Fifteen 240
Thousand)
2020-21 1576 1298 2021-22 813 322 1250000(Twelve Lakh 159
Fifty Thousand)
Ph.D Student Details
Ph.D (Student pursuing doctoral program till 2021-22)
Total Students
Full Time 3114
Part Time 630
No. of Ph.D students graduated (including Integrated Ph.D)
2021-22 2020-21 2019-20
Full Time 238 230 228
Part Time 69 71 98
Financial Resources: Utilised Amount for the Capital Expenditure for previous 3 years
Financial Year 2021-22 2020-21 2019-20
Utilised Amount Utilised Amount Utilised Amount
Annual Capital Expenditure on Academic Activities and Resources (excluding expenditure on buildings)
Library ( Books, Journals and e-Resources only) 183339247 (Eighteen Crore Thirty Three Lakh Thirty Nine 165806523 (Sixteen Crore Fifty Eight Lakh Six Thousand Five 170086147 (Seventeen Crore Eighty Six Thousand One
Thousand Two Hundrede Forty Seven) Hundred Twenty Three) Hundred Forty Seven)
New Equipment and software for Laboratories 2372989697 (Two Hundred Thirty Seven Crore Twenty Nine 1599172098 (One Hundred Fifty Nine Crore Ninety One Lakh 1827027685 (One Hundred Eighty Two Crore Seventy Lakh
Lakh Eighty Nine Thousand Six Hundred Ninety Seven) Seventy Two Thousand Ninety Eight) Twenty Thousand Six Hundred Eighty Five)
Engineering Workshops 44456874 (Four Crore Forty Four Lakh Fifty Six Thousand 3399314 (Thirty Three Lakh Ninety Nine Thousand Three 4058686 (Forty Lakh Fifty Eight Eight Thousand Six Hundred
Eight Hundred Seventy Four) Hundred Fourteen) Eighty Six)
Other expenditure on creation of Capital Assets (For setting up 1396232731 (One Hunred Thirty Nine Crore Sixty Two Lakh 875256347 (Eighty Seven Crore Fifty Two Lakh Fifty Six 745381664 (Seventy Four Crore Fifty Three Lakh Eighty One
classrooms, seminar hall, conference hall , library, Lab, Engg Thirty Thousand Seven Hundred Thirty One) Thousand Three Hundred Forty Seven) Thousand Six Hundred Sixty Four)
workshops excluding expenditure on Land and Building)
Financial Resources: Utilised Amount for the Operational Expenditure for previous 3 years
Financial Year 2021-22 2020-21 2019-20Utilised Amount Utilised Amount Utilised Amount
Annual Operational Expenditure
Salaries (Teaching and Non Teaching staff) 3899613736 (Three Hundred Eighty Nine Crore Ninety Six 3395121711 (Three Hundred And Thirty Nine Crore Fifty One 3428644542 (Three Forty Two Crore Eighty Six Lakh Forty
Lakh Thirteen Thousand Seven Hundred Thirty Six) Lakh Twenty One Thousand Seven Hundred Eleven) Four Thousand Five Hundred Forty Two)
Maintenance of Academic Infrastructure or consumables and 3659085996 (Three Hundred Sixty Five Crore Ninety Lakh 3637475618 (Three Hundred Sixty Three Crore Seventy Four 3200750453 (Three Hundred And Twenty Crore Seven Lakh
other running expenditures(excluding maintenance of hostels Eighty Five Thousand Nine Hundred Ninety Six) Lakh Seventy Five Thousand Six Hundred Eighteen) Fifty Thousand Four Hundred Fifty Three)
and allied services,rent of the building, depreciation cost, etc)
Seminars/Conferences/Workshops 2654267 (Twenty Six Lakh Fifty Four Thousand Two Hundred 5348744 (Fifty Three Lakh Forty Eight Thousand Seven 13001549 (One Crore Thirty Lakh One Thousand Five
Sixty Seven) Hundred Forty Four) Hundred Forty Nine)
Sponsored Research Details
Financial Year 2021-22 2020-21 2019-20
Total no. of Sponsored Projects 714 581 624
Total no. of Funding Agencies 213 205 195
Total Amount Received (Amount in Rupees) 3748347370 2614152161 2275026000
Amount Received in Words Three Hundred Seventy Four Crore Eighty Three Lakh Forty Two Hundred Sixty One Crore Forty One Lakh Fifty Two Two Hundred Twenty Seven Crore Fifty Lakh Twenty Six
Seven Thousand Three Hundred Seventy Thousand One Hundred Sixty One Thousand
Consultancy Project Details
Financial Year 2021-22 2020-21 2019-20
Total no. of Consultancy Projects 368 355 362
Total no. of Client Organizations 314 299 318
Total Amount Received (Amount in Rupees) 431097403 377449556 309608826
Amount Received in Words Forty Three Crore Ten Lakh Ninety SZeven Thousand Four Thirty Seven Crore Seventy Four Lakh Forty Nine Thousand Thirty Crore Ninety Six Lakh Eight Thousand Eight Hundred
Hundred Three Five Hundred Fifty Six Twenty Six
PCS Facilities: Facilities of Physically Challenged Students
1. Do your institution buildings have Lifts/Ramps? Yes, more than 80% of the buildings
2. Do your institution have provision for walking aids, including wheelchairs and transportation from one building to another for Yes
handicapped students?
3. Do your institution buildings have specially designed toilets for handicapped students? Yes, more than 80% of the buildings
Faculty Details
Number of faculty members entered 919
